Reading Task
The Polynesian Cultural Center
Some theme parks are not only amusing, but also educational.
Take the Polynesian Cultural Center (PCC) in Hawaii for example.
It not only shows visitors the Polynesian way of life but also protects their skills
and culture for the future.
Polynesia is the name given to the many groups of small islands
that are spread about the Pacific Ocean.
The PCC is set in 42 acres of beautiful countryside where visitors can see seven different traditional
Polynesian island villages.
Villagers from many island communities(社团) come to show visitors their styles of dress
and different customs.
For example, you can see different skills of the villagers.
They also tell you about their social customs and show you their cooking methods
and their dances.
Their most important skill is boat-building,
which allowed the islanders to explore all the islands in the Polynesian Triangle.
They were able to find their way using the smell of the wind,
the movements of the fish and seaweed,
and the height and direction of the waves.
They were very clever sailors.
Now they use those boat-building skills to make long boats
and show the races and battles that they took part in long ago.
All this helps keep the skills and technology of the island people alive.